Kishan Narotam

Senior Associate Consultant +27 72 619 1929 knarotam@gmail.com knarotam.github.io Johannesburg, South Africa KEY SKILLS Time & Self Management Communication Leadership Complex Problem Solving Analytical Skills (Business and Data)

EDUCATION

Software Development

MBA in Business Analytics

Universidad Catolica San Antonio de Murcia | Spain to be completed in 2022

Postgraduate Extended Diploma in Business Management

Cambridge International Qualifications | UK to be completed in 2022

Bachelor of Science in Engineering (Electrical) Information

University of the Witwatersrand | South Africa 2019

IEB National Senior Certificate with Advanced Programme Mathematics

St John's College | South Africa 2012

INDUSTRIES

Logistics & Market Research Education & Training ICT (Information & Communication Technologies) Engineering Insurance

***** DEMOGRAPHICS

Gender · Male
Disability · None
Race · Indian
Languages · English

Banking

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Senior Associate Consultant currently working as a *Data Analyst* at *IQbusiness*, with an always learning mentality and seeks to apply himself to his maximum potential. Having worked on various projects where his role ranged from lead engineer to a business analyst and a data analyst, Kishan's approach to work is methodical and analytical. The execution of the task is planned accordingly, to complete all objectives in the most efficient and successful manner so that the maximum value can be added. Kishan is in the process of completing his MBA specialised in Business Analytics through UCAM University.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Consultant · IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa # 11/02/2021 - Current

Responsibilities: Kishan is consulting to Nedbank as a Data Analyst within the Ghost Team in optimising the overall data management process. This includes sourcing data in order to create the baseline metric; creating a dashboard and report that can be presented to both business and technical stakeholders; ensuring POPIA compliance in all processes and implementations.

Associate Consultant

29/01/2020 - 11/02/2021

Responsibilities: Kishan has worked as a business analyst on an internal project as well as an external project. He has successfully performed the role of a Data Analyst for Genex Insights and worked as an analyst within Absa's model risk space that would lead to a tactical journey in 2021.

Teaching Assistant · University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2019 - 10/2019

m 07/2018 - 10/2018

Responsibilities: Kishan was required to help run, execute and demonstrate laboratories and tutorials. In doing so he required extensive knowledge of C++, SFML, GitHub and Git collaboration. Throughout the course, Kishan assisted the students in a variety of ways relating to their work.

Intern · Liberty Life Head Office | Johannesburg, South Africa

07/2017

28/11/2016 - 18/01/2017

06/05/2016 - 17/06/2016

Responsibilities: Kishan worked in the IT department of the company assisting the HOD in various projects. The projects tasked to Kishan ranged from data collection, database management, network mapping, system analysis, C++ and VBA programming and Excel programming.

Responsibilities: Kishan was challenged with analysing C# code for an ongoing project and was tasked with converting the project into C++. Following this, Kishan had to design and implement a basic user interface for the analysed code.

Kishan Narotam

TOOLKIT

Software Development

MATLAB · C++ · Java · HTML · CSS · NodeJS · Assembly · Python

Project Management

Scrum · Kanban · MS Project · Trello · Test Driven Development

Databases

MySQL · MS Access · Netezza

Continuous Integration

Analysis

MS Excel · Power BI · Tableau

Technical Writing

MS Word · MS PowerPoint · MS Outlook · MS Visio · LaTeX

Graphical Editing

Adobe Premiere Pro



IBM (Coursera)

Data Science Professional Certificate (IBM Data Science) · 16/01/2021

Data Science Foundations Specialization · 08/12/2020

Applied Data Science Capstone · 16/01/2021

Machine Learning with Python · 14/01/2021

Data Analysis with Python · 24/12/2020

Databases and SQL for Data Science · 08/12/2020

Python for Data Science and AI · 01/12/2020

Data Science Methodology · 20/11/2020

Tools for Data Science · 17/11/2020

Data Science Orientation · 10/11/2020

Microsoft

MTA: Database Fundamentals: Certificate 2020 15/09/2020

ICAgile

ICAgile Certified Professional · 04/05/2020

Tableau

Tableau Author · 29/05/2020 Tableau Consumer · 26/05/2020

IQbusiness

UX Design Bootcamp · 21/08/2020

UiPath Academy

RPA Business Analyst Foundation · 12/08/2020 RPA Starter Training · 03/03/2020



in /in/kishan-y-narotam/

/KNarotam

/JoKishler

(i) /JoKishler

/JoKishler

== PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst · Ghost Squad

Nedbank Group | Johannesburg, South Africa

01/02/2021 - Current

Project Overview: The Ghost ecosystem is responsible for unsecured lending in Nedbank, namely credit card, personal loan, overdraft and home loans. The overall objective is to optimise the pipeline and its environment to ensure improved efficiency and monitoring while complying to regulations. This includes documenting all necessary process; understanding and analysing all procedures and subsequent data.

Responsibilities: Kishan has created a holistic document that entails detailed explanations and process diagrams of the Ghost pipelines' procedures, source to target mapping and solutions and analysis of various queries; being made available in a centralised location. Kishan has also analysed various optimisation implementations, documenting and creating a dashboard for ongoing monitoring and evaluation that can be utilised by both business and technical teams alike. Kishan was also tasked in analysing the processes within the pipeline and ensuring and documenting all POPIA related aspects ensuring compliance of the system.

Analyst · Model Risk Data Discovery and Design Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 28/07/2020 - 11/12/2020

Project Overview: The model risk architecture and processes for credit regulatory reporting are sub-optimal in terms of business efficiencies being realised across the value chain. The project team developed a target state architecture and roadmap identifying opportunities for unlocking sustainable efficiency. Subsequently, the project team took the various stakeholders through various roadshow presentations to gain valuable buy-in on the identified opportunities and created a project charter for the initiatives.

Responsibilities: Kishan was an analyst supporting the team in a variety of manners. In the first phase of the project, Kishan defined various role profiles for stakeholders in the model risk space, mapped out necessary frameworks, policies and standards for a clearer understanding. In the subsequent phase, Kishan assisted in creating a project charter for a tactical journey that will occur in 2021, identifying benefits and associated metrics.

Data Analyst · MultiChoice Africa Genex Insights | Johannesburg, South Africa

09/03/2020 - 31/07/2020

Project Overview: The project involved working on the MultiChoice Africa account within the CX team, where the data's integrity had to be investigated and monitored. In conjunction to this assisting the team in applying various methodologies that would allow the team to become more proactive in handling the account, and to improve relationships between the MultiChoice Africa and Genex Insights.

Responsibilities: Kishan was placed as a Data Analyst within the Genex Insights' CX team initially investigating a data discrepancy issue, utilising the Genex Insights VOC platform to assist with data retrieval, mapping & managing for MultiChoice Africa. Kishan also updated & created new dashboard views for surveys that had existed & were introduced respectively. Kishan's understanding of the platform gave him the opportunity to train new MultiChoice members on using the platform, while handling queries daily.

Kishan Narotam

TESTIMONIALS

Kishan is a quick learner, keen to assist and jump right in without any hesitation. The attitude he brings to his work speaks a great deal about his character. This is seen in all interactions (meetings, written communications) with him. He is a genuine team player. I have worked with a variety of analysts of the years. Kishan has qualities and characteristics that is increasingly becoming rare in the work environment. He is a true professional and an asset to any organisation.

Kesava Naidoo | Ghost Squad Data Team Product Owner

Nedbank Group Limited | 2021

Kishan is a bright, eager team member who contributes more that his share of the workload. He shows signs of leadership potential and it is suggested that he is offered opportunities to develop these leadership qualities further. He is adaptable to the situation of the project and covers areas of uncertainty with research and skills development.

Tamas Salamon | Manager IQbusiness | 2021

Thank you for all that you have brought to this team - you have gone above and beyond- and have shown incredible grit. Your solution orientation and team player attitude is definitely going to take you places! Please continue to stay in touch with the team - you have been invaluable. And such an integral contributor to the momentum created on the MAL account. Thank you for all your effort.

Kirana Singh | Customer Experience Manager Genex Insights | 2020

Working with you for 4 months has been a great experience. You contributed immensely to stabilising the account with your proactive work ethic and tireless attitude to making things "work". Your technical skills and great understanding of data/software made life that much easier with a bulk of the queries - we had way too many "Kishan-type queries" and working closely with you taught me a whole lot as well.

Yonela Rozani | MAH Account Manager Genex Insights | 2020

Great ability to think on your feet and find solutions, and always looking for an opportunity or reason why something might be wrong as opposed to going into panic mode, you work well under pressure. Very punctual. You have never ran late on submissions and even closed out on queries earlier than the deadline. Resilience and GRIT, I really admire your ability to remain positive and focus on way forward when we are faced with challenges.

Phindile Vilakazi | Research Executive Genex Insights | 2020

It was an absolute pleasure having you on our team!! You have added tremendous value and assisted in getting it over the line with client.

Sumaya Naidoo | HR Manager Genex Insights | 2020

PROJECT EXPERIENCE CONT...

Business Analyst · IQbusiness Talent Management Solution IQbusiness | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 06/02/2020 - 25/02/2020

Project Overview: IQbusiness required a proposal for a solution which would aid in the improvement of their current talent management processes, allowing employees and managers to monitor personal development and talent.

Responsibilities: Kishan was part of the business requirements team, whose responsibility was focused on creating the business requirements document, by consolidating prior teams work. Kishan was also part of the governance team and took control of consolidating the project initiation document for the final proposal, as well as presenting the final proposal.

Business Analyst · IAM AfricaAccess | CSO Testing Proposal Absa Group Limited | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 30/01/2020 - 04/02/2020

Project Overview: The IAM project was an enhancement on Absa's existing Access Management System, which looked into adding an amend capability. The testing project looked at proposing an idea for a separate testing team to be created within Absa's CSO team.

Responsibilities: Kishan worked as a Junior business analyst, and his responsibilities involved creating the initial draft of the business requirements document. The testing project involved creating a proposal for the testing team based on research and best practices.

Lead Engineer · Design of a Thermally Controlled System for Medications University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 17/09/2019 - 25/10/2019

Project Overview: The project involved designing a thermal system that can control the temperature of medication in it. The design was unique based on current literature and simulated in a multiphysics programme.

Responsibilities: The lead engineer had to design and simulate the designed container making sure that the design was tested utilising free-to-use multiphysics programme, calculating cost & power concerns. Subsequently, the project was documented accordingly.

Co-Lead Engineer · Image Compression Based on Non-Parametric Sampling in Noisy Environments

University of the Witwatersrand | Johannesburg, South Africa **#** 01/07/2019 - 11/09/2019

Project Overview: The aim of the project was to create a method of image compression that involved creating holes in the image, encoding, transmitting said image through a noisy channel and filling these holes.

Responsibilities: Kishan created, implemented and developed the compression scheme based on current existing schemes. The compression scheme was tested and analysed against existing schemes and the results were documented accordingly.